# 大家好
Hi everyone!
# 我帶了點這個地籠
I'm taking some, you see, some traps,
# 去抓點那個魚來養 (註︰他現在說是養，後來說是用油炸)
to catch some, you know, some fish back home,
# 在河裡面抓
from the river,
# 在下面
down there.
# 你看 這個好靚啊 肯定很多魚
Look! It's so beautiful! There must be a lot of fish.
# 這個是新網來的哦
This is a new trap, you know.
# 還是去年買的
But it was bought last year.
# 沒有繩子啦
There's no string.
# 我去找一(個)[SIC]根繩子來
Let me fetch a piece of string.
# 好啦 放好一個啦
Alright! I'm done with this one.
# 還有幾個放到下面去
There's a couple more. I'm gonna put them down there.
# 還有兩副網 放到一下面去
There are two more. Let me put them down there.
# 現在已經搞好了哦
So now we're done.
# 放下地籠啦 明天我們再過來收
All the traps have been placed. We'll come again tomorrow to get them back.
# 第二天
The next day
# 昨天晚上我做夢
I made a dream yesterday night.
# 看到那個一地龍都是那個草魚呀 鯉魚呀 鯽魚呀 (註︰這裡有作太多翻譯了，總之一大堆魚吧)
In the dream, I saw the traps were filled with, you know, carps, grass carps, and many others.
# 好多 好多魚
A lot and a lot of fish!
# 還有石斑魚
And cichlids too!
# 我帶一個那麼大的桶去裝 把它裝滿帶回家
I'm going with such a huge bucket and come back with the bucket filled with fish.
# 我們到河邊啦 就好那邊 去看一下
We're now at the riverside. It's right over there. Let's take a look.
# 肯定有魚
There must be fish.
# 就一條泥鰍
Just a pond loach
# 哎呀 好重啊
Aya! It's so heavy!
# 難道又沒有
Nothing again?
# 兩個小蝦米
Two tiny little shrimps
# 你看 這個小蝦米
Look! The tiny little shrimps,
# 很小哦
are really small.
# 先放在這裡 看一下其它的
I put it here first, and have a look at the other traps.
# 全是泥巴
Nothing but mud
# 一條都沒有
There's not even one fish.
# 你看就摘了那麼一點 (註︰我覺得他應該是說「抓」，不要「摘」)
Look! We have just a tiny little bit here.
# 昨天沒有放餌料
I didn't put any bait yesterday.
# 肯定沒餌料(的原因) 不然怎麼會那麼一點點吧
Yea, no bait! Otherwise I wouldn't have just a tiny little bit here.
# 全是小魚
All are small fish.
# 你看 這條拿沙狗子
Look! This is a goby.
# 這條是花鯽魚 長不大的 就那麼大一點
This is a "hua ji yu". It's always that small. It won't get any bigger.
# 這是石斑魚
This is a cichlid.
# 這是泥鰍
And this is a pond loach,
# 蝦米
small shrimps.
# 還不夠一餐
That's not even enough for a meal.
# 如果多一點的話 可以拿回去油炸一下 很好吃的哦
I could have them fried if there are more. I would be really tasty!
# 現在太少啦
But now it's too few.
# 把它放掉
Let me just release them.
# 回歸自然
Back to the nature
# 下次不要進網了啊
Don't come into the trap next time, got it?
# 那麼小
You guys are so small.
# 下次我放點餌料進去 要抓大魚 這個小魚抓得沒意思 太小啦
I'll put some bait next time. I want big fish. The small fish are far too small. It's not fun at all.
# 下次我搞點餌料來
I'll come with some bait next time.
# 我又沒放餌料抓了那麼小
Without the bait, there are only small fish.
# 把你們放走吧
Let me release you guys.
# 放點哦 不然 你們自由了
Hurry up! Otherwise.... You're free now.
# 加油 加油 誰跑得快一點
Keep going, keep going! Let's see who is the fastest.
# 逆水而上
They're swimming against the current.
# 好多都逆水而上啦
Many are already swimming against the current.
# 誰不上的 我拿回去
Those who are not swimming, are to go back home with me,
# 我拿回去用油炸一下
back home with me, and to be fried in oil.
# 全部都往上爬
They're all swimming upwards.
# 快點跑哦 不跑就沒機會啦
C'mon! Hurry up! This is your last chance!
# 全跑啦 就剩下一條泥鰍
All have run away, except this pond loach.
# 泥鰍你怎麼那麼笨 走哇
Why are you do stupid, pond loach? Just go!
# 等一下今天晚上就把你那個煮啦哦 跑啦
Otherwise I'll have you cooked tonight. Alright it has left.
# 好啦 今天的視頻就到這裡啦
Alright! The video ends here.
# 回去啦
Let's go back.
# 抓了那麼小的魚 沒意思
The fish are so small. It's not fun at all.
# 桶又帶一個那麼大的來
I came with such a large bucket.
# 就沒裝到
But it's still empty.